<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nataliazhang.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://nataliazhang.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-06-17T09:32:37+00:00</updated><id>https://nataliazhang.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Natalia Zhang</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Final Match of the Shuimu Cup</title><link href="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2025/softball/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Final Match of the Shuimu Cup"/><published>2025-05-27T04:52:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-27T04:52:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2025/softball</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2025/softball/"><![CDATA[<p>The final game of the Shuimu Cup on May 25th, 2025 was, without a doubt, the most exhilarating match of my college years.</p> <div style="text-align: center;"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/teamline.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"/> </div> <p>Three home runs from the opponents carved out a seemingly unbridgeable chasm. The game was dragged into extra innings, taut with tension. Then—came the comeback, the lead, and the victory.</p> <p>The full-throttle moments frozen by Donnie’s lens, the deafening roar from the stands, the stacked hands cheering as one, and finally, the whole team bursting onto the field in a sweeping embrace.</p> <p>All those colors, all that passion—enough to outshine even the most intense scenes from a shōnen manga.</p> <div style="text-align: center;"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/scoreboard.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"/> </div> <p>As if in response to the wish I had made at the beginning of the Shuimu Cup, fate granted me a finale as exhilarating as I had dared to dream.</p> <p>Though I’m usually the one in the outfield immersed in “spectator mode,” this time, even on defense, I felt utterly, vividly present.</p> <p>The rundown play passed through five swift and steady hands before the final tag landed in mine. With the foresight of a god, our coach Richard called for a shift—so precise that the final out landed straight into my glove.</p> <p>Twice I got on base with clean hits to second, and both times my teammates brought me home.</p> <div style="text-align: center;"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/tag.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"/> </div> <p>When we were down to our very last out from a total defeat, it was my turn at bat. “Don’t be nervous!” Shark yelled from first base—yet his nervous couldn’t hide its own nerves.</p> <p>But come on—that’s me.</p> <p>My dictionary doesn’t include pressure in the face of failure. My favorite storyline is the one where the tide is turned. And if my effort alone isn’t enough to turn it, then my teammates will rise and keep turning it.</p> <p>Even in the bleakest moments of the game, I carried a ridiculous, contradictory kind of optimism:<br/> Half calm—“Even if we lose, this was already epic.”<br/> Half cocky—“How could a game with me in it possibly end in defeat?”</p> <p>And when the comeback became reality, all those stumbles and near-defeats turned into narrative thorns in a classic tale, making the final crown all the more precious and sweet.</p> <div style="text-align: center;"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/tangle.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"/> </div> <p>When the people around me tacitly stepped aside to form a circle and called out my name and Yutong’s in unison, I was still sitting dumbfounded on the grass, a single thought spinning in my head:<br/> “Huh? Am I really today’s lucky lead?”</p> <p>It wasn’t until someone handed me a bouquet of flowers that it truly hit me—<br/> This was my final game in the Tsinghua Garden.</p> <div style="text-align: center;"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/book1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"/> </div> <p>Trophy, flowers, a custom cake with my name iced on top, a lovingly handmade scrapbook, a thick stack of photos and blessings, the laughter captured by Donnie’s lens, and our tangled, tired bodies sprawled out on the grass together.</p> <p>Just as I never dared to hope for such a spectacular match to close this journey, I never imagined I’d be the one standing at its center, wrapped in such a romantic farewell.<br/> So complete.</p> <div style="text-align: center;"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/book2.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"/> </div> <p>Unwittingly, four years had passed with this team. I had become someone the coach could be proud of, someone teammates could rely on, someone juniors might admire—and now, I would quietly become a part of Tsinghua softball’s memory.</p> <p>What a beautiful way for it all to end.</p> <div style="text-align: center;"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/glove_photos.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"/> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Game That Stayed With Me]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">School Softball Team</title><link href="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/softball/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="School Softball Team"/><published>2024-11-23T12:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-23T12:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/softball</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/softball/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="softball-and-me">Softball and Me</h2> <p>Softball is a fantastic sport! I started playing softball when I entered Tsinghua University in 2021, and it has been my favorite sport ever since.</p> <p>Visit my WeChat post <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/fWlLqW4PSBXamksC2DPTAg">here</a> to learn about my story with softball in Tsinghua!</p> <p>As an outfielder, I love to chase down fly balls. When I’m on the field, my teammates trust me to make the catch, and I try my best to fulfill their trust. It’s the combination of teamwork and individual effort that makes softball so special.</p> <div style="text-align: center; margin-bottom: 20px;"> A nice catch I made at the game with BBS! </div> <div style="text-align: center; display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 20px;"> <figure style="margin: 0;"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/fly_ball_1.png" alt="Fly Ball 1" style="height: 200px; width: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Tracking the ball in the air</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure style="margin: 0;"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/fly_ball_2.png" alt="Fly Ball 2" style="height: 200px; width: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Ready to catch it</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure style="margin: 0;"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/fly_ball_3.png" alt="Fly Ball 3" style="height: 200px; width: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Landing the perfect catch</em></figcaption> </figure> </div> <p>Batting is my favorite part. The moment I step into the batter’s box, I get the control of the game.</p> <div style="text-align: center; display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 20px;"> <figure style="margin: 0;"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/batting_1.jpg" alt="batting 1" style="height: 200px; width: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Waiting for the perfect pitch</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure style="margin: 0;"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/batting_2.png" alt="batting 2" style="height: 200px; width: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Hit!</em></figcaption> </figure> </div> <h2 id="tsinghua-softball-team-a-season-of-passion-and-teamwork">Tsinghua Softball Team: A Season of Passion and Teamwork</h2> <p>This season, <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/fAQn931Is67_s0rR73rMow">Tsinghua softball team</a> has had an amazing journey, filled with thrilling moments, teamwork, and unforgettable experiences. From intense practices to championship victories, we has given it our all. I’m proud to be part of this team, making an effort to contribute to our success.</p> <div style="text-align: center; margin-bottom: 20px;"> <figure> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/champion_group.jpg" alt="Champion Group Photo" style="max-width: 60%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>The winning team of Beijing Collegiate Softball Tournament</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/champion_cheer.jpg" alt="Championship Cheer" style="max-width: 60%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Our lovely softball girls celebrating the victory</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/fly_ball_purple.png" alt="On the Game" style="max-width: 60%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>During the game</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="/assets/img/blog/softball/champion_individual.jpg" alt="Individual Champion" style="max-width: 40%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>This is the second champion we get in Beijing Collegiate Softball Tournament, since I joined the school team.</em></figcaption> </figure> </div> <p>This season has been a testament to the hard work, teamwork, and passion that defines our softball team. We are ready for the challenges of next season, and we know we will be even stronger.</p> <p>Our coach quoted the following lines to inspire us to embody the spirit of teamwork. These are from <em>Teammate: My Journey in Baseball and a World Series for the Ages</em> by David Ross, former Chicago Cubs catcher.</p> <ul> <li>to be honest with everyone around you,</li> <li>to be humble no matter how good things get,</li> <li>to be reliable and consistent so that everyone knows what to expect,</li> <li>to willingly share your experiences with others,</li> <li>to manage change with a smile and stay engaged with everyone so that you can know how best to inspire them.</li> </ul> <p>These exactly define our team. We are teammates, and we are family. We are Tsinghua softball team, and we are champions.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="softball"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Games and practices in the Tsinghua softball team]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">US City Impressions</title><link href="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/city/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="US City Impressions"/><published>2024-08-22T01:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-22T01:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/city</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/city/"><![CDATA[<p>If Seattle feels like a relaxed coastal town, its life nourished by gentle sea breezes and light rain, surrounded by ivy-covered walls and lush shrubbery, then Boston is like a pristine rose garden basking in sunlight, where every street and building is meticulously arranged. Walking through the campuses of Harvard and MIT, we witness the idealized vision of what a university campus should be. Like something out of a movie, with red brick walls, green lawns, and students rushing between lecture halls, full of youthful energy and the crisp air of academia.</p> <p>New York, however, held a different anticipation for me. Before I set foot there, I imagined it as an exclusive, luxurious metropolis. But after walking its streets, it revealed itself to me as a chaotic, vibrant city of boundless energy. The subway brought us to iconic sights, past bustling construction sites and turning corners into towering glass skyscrapers. On the Brooklyn Bridge, pedestrians flowed continuously, while street vendors laid out baseball caps and metallic trinkets. Snake charmers paraded their docile snakes, interacting with the kids around them. The sun fragmented across the webbed cables of the bridge, as young people in trendy clothes captured punk-inspired photos with the changing light.</p> <p>In reality, few places have ever given me the sense of “grandeur” I expected from a metropolis. Even Manhattan, the island said to be a land of precious real estate, didn’t feel much more overwhelming than the city centers of Beijing or Shanghai, or even the new districts in my hometown, Hangzhou, which have blossomed in the past decade. Only from the top of the Empire State Building, once the tallest skyscraper in the world, did I catch a brief glimpse of the city’s economic dominance, with its breathtaking skyline at night. Down below, Times Square offered an even more vivid spectacle—neon lights and giant LED screens flashing in every direction, surrounded by crowds of people dancing and cheering.</p> <p>At the harbor, the massive Statue of Liberty held her torch high, a symbol of both solemnity and freedom. Visitors gathered beneath her feet, raising their own flame-shaped lemonaide cups in a festive pose. Tourists of every color flowed through exhibition halls, while in a giant interactive photo wall, smiling faces merged to form a colorful heart. The iconic crown of the Statue of Liberty was humorously reimagined in souvenir shops, as “liberty penguins,” “liberty dolphins,” and “liberty ducks.”</p> <p>This port city, built by waves of immigrants, stands as a testament to the spirit of liberty. The Statue of Liberty greets all ships entering the harbor, welcoming travelers and returning citizens. She and the spirit of freedom she embodies are not reverently worshiped on a pedestal, but instead are casually scattered into the lives of everyday people, just as the word “freedom” suggests.</p> <p>As my flight took off from New York’s airport, I looked out the window and saw an even more spectacular view than from the Empire State Building. The plane’s wing cut through the sky, and the lights below formed a whip-like arc, stretching across the vast expanse of land. As the city beneath me unfolded, it looked like a single sheet of land, a vast curtain of earth rising into the horizon.</p> <p>At night, New York feels like a pulsating heart in the darkness. From above, the city’s lights intertwine in golden and silver threads, breathing in and out, like blood vessels pulsing through the night.</p> <p>I’ve never felt a city so vividly alive.</p> <div style="text-align: center; margin-bottom: 20px;"> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\7.1.jpg" alt="City 1" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>MIT Campus</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\7.2.jpg" alt="City 2" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Brooklyn Bridge</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\7.3.jpg" alt="City 3" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Statue of Liberty</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\7.4.jpg" alt="City 4" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Souvenir shops with animals of liberty</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\7.5.jpg" alt="City 5" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>New York City at night</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\8.1.jpg" alt="City 5" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Amazon Sphere in Seattle</em></figcaption> </figure> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="internship"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Impressions of Seattle, Boston, and New York]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exhibitions at US</title><link href="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/exhibition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exhibitions at US"/><published>2024-07-05T02:18:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-05T02:18:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/exhibition</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/exhibition/"><![CDATA[<p>During my travels in Seattle, New York, and Boston, I visited many exhibitions—ranging from formal art, science, and history museums to the more casual display booths around campus. From an observer’s perspective, I found that no matter the form, all these exhibitions shared the same nature: they reflect what the exhibitors want the audience to see. If they want people to see facts, they present them; if they want to convey emotions, they evoke them; if they want to share common values, they discuss them; if they want to inspire thought, they ignite it. Rather than focusing on the specific content of the exhibits, I’d like to reflect on these indirect, subtle observations and feelings.</p> <h2 id="911-memorial-museum">911 Memorial Museum</h2> <p>One way to understand a culture is by observing how it deals with disaster. After the 9/11 attacks, a memorial museum was built at the site of the former Twin Towers in New York.</p> <p>The dimly lit, serene, and solemn exhibition halls display firsthand news broadcasts from the day of the attack, capturing the first ripples of shock like a bomb dropped into a calm lake. Photographs of the victims cover the walls, along with their biographies. A timeline spanning multiple exhibition halls shows the words of those involved in the tragedy.</p> <p>What I saw was not an outpouring of anger, but a calm recounting; not a narrative filled with contradictions, but a compassionate remembrance. The exhibition presented little subjective interpretation, only an accumulation of facts. This museum shows people’s attitude toward natural and man-made disasters—grief born from empathy for the victims and remembrance out of respect for the deceased. The core emotion displayed here was not hate, but love.</p> <h2 id="american-museum-of-natural-history">American Museum of Natural History</h2> <p>Though it bears the name of a nation, the exhibits here are not limited to that of a single country. The scientific and natural history sections need no further description, but the cultural exhibits span across the globe: Native American hunting bows, ancient Egyptian kitchenware, Chinese bridal sedan chairs, and Japanese kimonos—all treated with equal importance.</p> <p>Most of the descriptions in the exhibits are scientific, factual accounts, with little or no moral or value-based commentary.</p> <p>Sometimes I wonder if our study of ancient peoples’ customs and lifestyles carries a sense of modern superiority. Like scientists studying animal societies, we analyze tribal practices and causes, placing ourselves in the position of objective researchers. But from another perspective, telling history without subjective emotion allows the audience to make their own judgments, avoiding undue influence from the researcher. The power to write history is often held by the victors of wars or those in power, so whether or not people can understand history’s true nature often depends on the restraint of those who write it.</p> <h2 id="uw-campus-science-fair">UW Campus Science Fair</h2> <p>On the UW display day, a swarm of elementary school students filled the campus, scattered across the various booths on the street. Thanks to the university students’ creative designs, science turned into magic, games, and performances, transforming dry knowledge into fun activities that children loved.</p> <p>A university is not just a place for students to hone their knowledge and skills; it is a bridge to pass on the passion and energy of science to the next generation. The university’s role is not to be an isolated research institute, but an active participant in the broader social ecosystem.</p> <div style="text-align: center; margin-bottom: 20px;"> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\6.1.jpg" alt="Exhibition 1" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>American Museum of Natural History display on ancient civilizations (1)</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\6.2.jpg" alt="Exhibition 2" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>American Museum of Natural History display on ancient civilizations (2)</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\6.3.jpg" alt="Exhibition 3" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Intrepid Museum</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\6.5.jpg" alt="Exhibition 5" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>UW display day</em></figcaption> </figure> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="internship"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Various exhibitions with facts, emotions, and values]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TGIF at UW</title><link href="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/tgif/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TGIF at UW"/><published>2024-04-28T16:31:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-28T16:31:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/tgif</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/tgif/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="friday-evening-allen-hall-lobby">Friday Evening, Allen Hall Lobby</h2> <p>It’s 6 PM on a Friday, and the sun is setting, casting long shadows on the ground. The imagined scent of dinner lures people on their way home, while inside, the soft fizz of sparkling water mixes with the murmur of casual conversation, creating a background buzz of disconnected sounds. After pondering the age-old questions of life — <em>Who am I? Where did I come from? Where am I going?</em> — my mind couldn’t shake the more immediate dilemma that had been nagging at me for the past hour and a half: <em>What on earth am I doing here?</em></p> <p>Normally, this space is a quiet lobby meant for studying. Before I found a stable spot in the lab to work, I often used to study here. As the CSE building, Allen Hall has a large open space with tables and chairs scattered across the hallways, offering a tranquil environment where students can focus. But tonight, I wasn’t here for studying.</p> <p>The reason I found myself in the lobby was a seemingly innocent email, a TGIF invitation. When I first arrived on campus, I was curious about everything, eager to experience new things. So, when I saw the invitation for a TGIF event (with words like <em>diamond painting</em> I had never heard of), I shrugged it off and decided to attend. After all, why not?</p> <h2 id="a-diamond-painting-session">A Diamond Painting Session</h2> <p>What followed was an hour and a half of… well, to be honest, rather monotonous work. The process of diamond painting involved picking up tiny rhinestones with a small stick, placing them on a circular base according to the pattern, and repeating this hundreds of times. I couldn’t help but reflect on how far removed this activity was from the high-tech, intellectually rigorous world I had imagined I would be part of in graduate school.</p> <p>At first, I was baffled. Why would a group of PhD students, the future of technology, spend their Friday evening engaging in such a simple, repetitive task? But as I glanced around, I noticed the other participants seemed to genuinely enjoy themselves, exchanging cheerful comments like “This is so fun!” and “I really like it!” I swallowed my confusion and carried on with the task.</p> <p>As I continued working, the mechanical repetition blurred my thoughts, and the space around me became a dizzying kaleidoscope of rhinestones. I couldn’t help but wonder: <em>Am I really here, participating in this?</em> The bizarre taste of unsweetened sparkling water added to the surreal feeling, leaving me unsure of how to engage with my surroundings. Yet, this odd moment in time made me question how easily we can get caught in the flow of things, even when the activity seems disconnected from our original expectations.</p> <p>By the time I left, I had a coaster covered in rhinestones, and an even more profound question lingering in my mind: <em>What was I doing here?</em></p> <h2 id="the-unexpected-tradition">The Unexpected Tradition</h2> <p>One week later, I found myself back in the same place. The email was the same, the activities were similar, but somehow, I was drawn in again. This time, there were ice carving competitions, egg dropping contests, a game of telephone drawing, water coloring, and baking. Each event, though simple in itself, seemed to speak to the creative minds of the students organizing it. The fun was subtle but continuous — a reflection of the endless flow of ideas that never seemed to run dry.</p> <p>The largest TGIF event I attended took place at the end of winter. The department organized a ski trip to the mountains. The bus wound its way up to the summit, where the landscape shifted dramatically from the springtime scenery below to a snow-covered winter wonderland at the top. As a first-time skier, I made a mistake and found myself on the blue run with no idea how to handle the steep slopes. When I froze at the top, a kind older student came to my rescue, guiding me step by step down the mountain. After the event, I didn’t master skiing, but I had gained something more: the courage to face new challenges, even when they seemed daunting at first.</p> <h2 id="more-than-just-a-tradition">More Than Just a Tradition</h2> <p>Later, I learned from a PhD student that TGIF wasn’t some prestigious acronym or grand title — it was simply a playful abbreviation for <em>Thank God It’s Friday!</em> In their words, it was a way for a group of PhD students, who spent most of their weekdays glued to their desks, to unwind and welcome the weekend. Every department at UW hosts their own TGIF events, with the school providing the venue and some basic snacks.</p> <p>Not everyone participates in the games. Many students simply stop by, grab some snacks, and chat with friends, filling the space with laughter and conversation. Despite my struggles with their enthusiasm for sugar-free sparkling water and odd-flavored chips, I came to appreciate these moments of casual relaxation. It’s a cultural phenomenon that contrasts sharply with the intense work mentality I was used to.</p> <p>For me, TGIF is a microcosm of a larger cultural shift — one where <em>work-life balance</em> isn’t an ideal to strive for but an ingrained way of life. Unlike my previous academic experience, where the boundaries between weekday and weekend were clear-cut, UW’s atmosphere taught me that time for both work and relaxation should be deliberately balanced. During the week, the study rooms and cafes are filled with focused students; but when the weekend comes, the offices empty out, leaving behind only the peaceful quiet of a well-earned break.</p> <h2 id="reflections">Reflections</h2> <p>As I left the last TGIF event, I realized that these little moments of joy, whether through making something with your hands or simply chatting over snacks, helped foster a sense of community. The events may have seemed trivial at first, but they revealed a different side of university life — one where it’s okay to step away from the pressure of work and embrace moments of light-hearted fun.</p> <p>TGIF was a cultural experience that reshaped my understanding of life as a graduate student. The work-life balance isn’t just a philosophy here — it’s a practice woven into every aspect of daily life.</p> <div style="text-align: center; margin-bottom: 20px;"> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\4.1.jpg" alt="TGIF Activity 1" style="max-width: 30%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Diamond painting</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\4.2.jpg" alt="TGIF Activity 2" style="max-width: 30%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Ice carving</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\4.3.jpg" alt="TGIF Activity 3" style="max-width: 30%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Painting the night sky</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\4.4.jpg" alt="TGIF Activity 4" style="max-width: 30%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Skiing at the summit</em></figcaption> &lt;/div&gt; </figure></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="internship"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A unique slice of student life at UW]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Impressions of Seattle</title><link href="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/impression/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Impressions of Seattle"/><published>2024-03-30T19:56:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-30T19:56:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/impression</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2024/impression/"><![CDATA[<p>When I first arrived in Seattle, it felt unremarkable—unremarkable in a way that reminded me of my hometown. Under the gray, overcast sky, the roads silently divided the city into a series of small, neat grids, and even the dogs out for a stroll were unusually quiet, hardly barking. The rain seemed endless, and on the streets, hardly anyone bothered with umbrellas, letting the raindrops soak their outerwear. Aside from that, there wasn’t much in this city that truly caught my attention.</p> <p>Flowers, birds, and dogs were the first things that UW (the University of Washington) left me with.</p> <p>The day I arrived at UW, the sky was dim, and the air was fresh with the sweetness of rain. In front of the library, I found myself lost in a sea of cherry blossom trees. Before this, I had never realized how tall cherry trees could grow. The clusters of flowers on the branches seemed to carefully wipe away the sweat from the sky, creating a soft pink veil. Beneath them, visitors strolled leisurely, rainwater mingling with the pollen, soaking into their collars. The fountains on campus sprayed water high into the air, their droplets shimmering against the gray sky. Standing in the distance, I captured this scene on my phone—my first photograph at UW, taken during the spring semester. As I ventured deeper into the campus, I saw students, like me, with backpacks—some riding skateboards, others on rollerblades, and some with dogs tugging at leashes, sprinting ahead on skateboards. The concept of spring, along with the cherry blossoms, flying birds, gentle rain, and passing pedestrians, grew and flourished all around me.</p> <p>It’s a twenty-minute walk from the dormitory to the department building, and along the way, I pass grassy lawns where Canadian geese forage, fountains where mallards and mandarin ducks glide, and the ever-present crows. Unlike the crows back at Tsinghua, which only circle above the dorms or occasionally drop their small “gifts” on the lucky ones below, the crows here seem unafraid of humans. They often gather in groups right at our feet, as if going about their business without a care. The only place I’ve seen crows circling overhead is inside the Allen Library’s atrium, where black bird models hang from the ceiling. I’ve heard that crows symbolize intelligence, or perhaps they are simply making a more straightforward statement: the world of knowledge is boundless, free like the birds themselves.</p> <p>The love for dogs, particularly Huskies, is especially prominent here at UW. After seeing the proud Husky statue outside the student activities building, it becomes clear that encountering dogs while walking through the park, studying in the library, or shopping in the mall is entirely ordinary. UW does not hide its affection for this mascot—the souvenir stores are brimming with Husky-themed items. Campus cards aren’t called “ID Cards,” but “Husky Cards,” and you need to show your “dog tag” to enter the library. Everywhere you go, you’ll find large signs that say “Washington Husky” near every stadium, and if you stand on the open lawn, you can almost hear the thunderous cheers for the Husky team on game days. Even in the restrooms, there’s a sign that says, “Stay Healthy, Huskies!” with a playful dog’s face. The Husky, symbolizing courage, energy, and loyalty, might seem more at home in an anime or novel than in a university setting, yet it fits perfectly at UW, where it flows seamlessly through the campus like a fish in water.</p> <p>Before I even had a chance to immerse my thoughts and intellect in this world, it had already captured my heart—just like the cherry blossoms in the rain, the birds at my feet, and the ever-glowing Huskies.</p> <div style="text-align: center; margin-bottom: 20px;"> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\3.1.jpg" alt="Impression 1" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Rainy Seattle day</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\3.2.jpg" alt="Impression 2" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Cherry blossoms in spring</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\3.3.jpg" alt="Impression 3" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Campus blend of nature and learning</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\3.4.jpg" alt="Impression 4" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Crows symbolizing knowledge</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\3.5.jpg" alt="Impression 5" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Campus Library</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="\assets\img\blog\internship\3.6.jpg" alt="Impression 6" style="max-width: 50%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Huskies’ pride and energy</em></figcaption> </figure> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="internship"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A journey through nature, animals and campus life in UW]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IIIS Student Festival</title><link href="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2023/chagpt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IIIS Student Festival"/><published>2023-12-26T02:12:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-26T02:12:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2023/chagpt</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nataliazhang.github.io/blog/2023/chagpt/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="chagpt-a-festival-of-creativity-and-innovation">ChaGPT: A Festival of Creativity and Innovation</h2> <p>In 2023, Tsinghua IIIS has held its first annual student festival, ChaGPT!</p> <p>I was honored to be one of the <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/_P434HVGuAwVGr5OFtBjUA">hosts</a>, taking the audience through a journey of creativity and innovation.</p> <div style="text-align: center; margin-bottom: 20px;"> <figure> <img src="/assets/img/blog/chagpt/group.jpg" alt="Group" style="max-width: 60%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Hosts of the festival</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="/assets/img/blog/chagpt/individual.jpg" alt="Individual" style="max-width: 60%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>On the stage</em></figcaption> </figure> <figure> <img src="/assets/img/blog/chagpt/pair.jpg" alt="Partner" style="max-width: 60%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>My partner and me</em></figcaption> </figure> </div> <p>Our class also presented a science fiction “Demory” at the festival. I acted the lead role as a student who traveled through memories to save the world.</p> <div style="text-align: center; margin-bottom: 20px;"> <figure> <img src="/assets/img/blog/chagpt/demory.jpg" alt="Science Fiction" style="max-width: 60%; height: auto;"/> <figcaption><em>Class Film from Yao 14</em></figcaption> </figure> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="ChaGPT"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ChaGPT, the annual student festival at IIIS]]></summary></entry></feed>